A Register of the Arch Puddington Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Arch Puddington collection
1947-1999
2001C73
Puddington, Arch, collector.
34 manuscript boxes, 5 card file boxes (15.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and sound recordings, relating to Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty. Used as research material for the book by A. Puddington, Broadcasting Freedom: The Cold War Triumph of Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty (Lexington, Ky., 2000). Includes records and photocopies of records of RFE/RL.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1944 February 10 Born, Louisville, Kentucky
1966 B.A., University of Missouri, Kansas City
1966-1968 Reporter, Lebanon Daily News, Pennsylvania
1968-1971 Political reporter, Bayonne Times, New Jersey
1971-1976 Program director, A. Philip Randolph Institute, New York City
1976-1985 Executive director, League for Industrial Democracy, New York City
1985-1993 Assistant director, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, New York office
1988 Author, Failed Utopias: Methods of Coercion in Communist Regimes
1993 Senior scholar, Freedom House, New York City
1994- Vice president for research, Freedom House, New York City
2000 Author, Broadcasting Freedom: The Cold War Triumph of Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty
2005 Author, Lane Kirkland: Champion of American Labor
Scope and Content of Collection
The Arch Puddington papers, acquired in 2001, consist of correspondence, memoranda, microfiche, photographs, printed matter, reports, and sound recordings relating to Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty. They were used as research material for the book by Arch Puddington, Broadcasting Freedom: The Cold War Triumph of Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty (Lexington, Kentucky, 2000). The collection includes records and photocopies of records of RFE/RL.
The bulk of the papers, contained in the Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty File, focus on the history of RFE/RL and its broadcasting policy. The effectiveness of its programs, as determined by governments and listeners in different countries, is reflected in Clippings and Printed Matter. Research Materials contains information relating to such issues as the beginnings, purpose, and future of RFE/RL, waves of internal dissent weakening RFE/RL as an instrument of U.S. policy, the question of its funding by the Central Intelligence Agency, and the role played by individuals and organizations in the activities of RFE/RL.
The inclusion of a substantial number of sound recordings complement the series previously mentioned.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 6 series: Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty File, Clippings and Printed Matter, Research Materials, Photographs, Microfiche from Congressional Information Service Microfiche Library, and Sound Recordings.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in Stanford University's online catalog.
Subjects
Radio Free Europe.; Radio Liberty (Munich, Germany); Radio broadcasting--Europe, Eastern.; Radio broadcasting--Soviet Union.; Phonotapes.; RFE/RL, inc.
Container List
- Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty File, 1949-2000 (Box 1)
  Briefing and fact books, correspondence, interview transcripts, memoranda, minutes of meetings, reports, statement, and subject files relating to RFE/RL history, broadcasting policy, strategic planning, and programs set up to target listeners in different countries, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General files, 1949 July – 1992 October. (Folder 1: 1-9)
    Includes clippings and printed matter, correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and survey reports relating to RFE/RL programs and their effectiveness, and the future of RFE/RL
  - Briefing book, 1974 July 4 (Folder 1: 10)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1975. (Box-folder 2: 1-7)
    Includes related materials
  - Fact Book, 1950-1973 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Interview with W. Griffith, Bonn, Germany, 1986 May 13 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Memoranda, 1951-1953 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Minutes of Planning Committee meetings, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
  - Policy and publicity manuals, 1959-1976 (Folder 3: 3-4)
  - Proceedings of conference on policy matters, 1961 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Records of the Department of Information Services, 1950-1973 (Folder 3: 6-8)
  - Reports
    - General
      - 1951-1956 (Folder 3: 9-10)
      - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Annual, 1968-1993 (Folder 4: 2-5)
    - Financial, 1973 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Kersten Committee on Communist aggression, 1954 (Folder 4: 7-8)
    - Media, 1971-1974 (Folder 4: 9-10)
    - President of the United States Task Force on U.S. Government International Broadcasting, 1991 December (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Publications and Special Projects Division, 1967-1969 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Watergate, 1973 (Folder 5: 3)
    - Weekly, 1958-1970 (Folder 5: 4)
    - West European Operations Report (WEOR), 1965 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Statement, "East Europe and Radio Free Europe in an 'Era of Negotiation'," submitted by William P. Durkee, 1971 June 14 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Subject file
    - General
      - 1950-1951. (Folder 5: 7-11)
        Consists of correspondence, memoranda, reports, and telegrams illustrating RFE/RL broadcasting policy guidelines and summary, record of monitoring broadcasts, and personnel records
      - 1952-1993 (Box-folder 6: 1-6)
      - Anti-Semitism, 1977–1986 (Folder 6: 7)
      - Bombing of Munich office, 1981 (Folder 6: 8-9)
      - London Program Center, 1950-1959 (Folder 6: 10)
      - Pentagon Papers, 1971(?) (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - Public relations, 1955-1958 (Folder 7: 2-3)
      - Radio programs rating and audience research. (Folder 7: 4-9)
        Includes East European Area Audience and Opinion Research (EEAOR), 1953-1982
      - Research materials and some chapters written for a book on Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty, 1950-1996 (Box-folder 8: 1-3)
      - Strategic planning, 1967-1993 (Folder 8: 4-7)
      - United States Congress
        - 1949-1999 (Folder 8: 8)
        - 1949-1999 (Box-folder 9: 1-8)
      - Winter Olympic Games (14th: 1984: Sarajevo, Bosnia and Hercegovina), 1984 February-April (Folder 9: 9)
    - Countries (Box 10)
      - General, 1974 (Folder 10: 1)
      - Albania, 1958 (Folder 10: 2)
      - Azerbaijan, 1990 (Folder 10: 3)
      - Baltic States, 1952-1991 (Folder 10: 4)
      - Cuba, 1962 (Folder 10: 5)
      - Czechoslovakia., See also Hungary
        - 1950-1966 (Folder 10: 6-16)
        - 1967-1998 (Box-folder 11: 1-9)
      - East Europe, 1963-1964 (Folder 11: 10-11)
      - Germany (Box 12)
        - 1951-1970 (Folder 12: 1-10)
        - 1970-2000 (Box-folder 13: 1-8)
      - Hungary., See also Czechoslovakia
        - 1950-1951 (Folder 13: 9-10)
        - 1951-1956 (Box-folder 14: 1-12)
        - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 15: 1-10)
        - 1956-1986 (Box-folder 16: 1-8)
      - Latin America, 1960-1961 (Folder 16: 9)
      - Poland
        - 1950-1951 (Folder 16: 10-12)
        - 1952-1956 (Box-folder 17: 1-10)
        - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 18: 1-9)
        - 1958-1996 (Box-folder 19: 1-12)
      - Romania, 1964-1974 (Folder 19: 13)
      - Serbia and Montenegro (former Yugoslavia), 1953-1962 (Box-folder 20: 1)
      - Soviet Union, 1953-1988 (Folder 20: 2-6)
- Clippings and Printed Matter, 1952-1995.
  Arranged alphabetically by language of material
  - English.
    - 1952-1961 (Folder 20: 7)
    - 1954-1969 (Folder 20: 8-9)
    - 1957-1971 (Folder 20: 10)
    - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - 1972 (Folder 21: 2)
    - 1973-1976 (Folder 21: 3-5)
    - 1976-1977 (Folder 21: 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Folder 21: 7)
    - 1980-1981 (Folder 21: 8)
    - 1982 (Folder 21: 9)
    - 1983 (Folder 21: 10-11)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 22: 1-3)
    - 1985 (Folder 22: 4-5)
    - 1986 (Folder 22: 6-7)
    - 1987 (Folder 22: 8)
    - 1987-1988 (Folder 22: 9)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
    - 1989 (Folder 23: 3-4)
    - 1990 (Folder 23: 5-7)
    - 1991 (Folder 23: 8-10)
    - 1991-1994 (Box-folder 24: 1-6)
  - French, 1970-1995 (Folder 24: 7)
  - German, 1952-1989 (Folder 24: 8)
  - Polish, 1971-1979 (Folder 24: 9)
  - Russian
    - 1954-1970 (Folder 24: 10-13)
    - 1970-1984 (Box-folder 25: 1-12)
    - 1985-1994 (Box-folder 26: 1-12)
- Research Materials, 1947-1996. (Box 27)
  Correspondence, interview transcripts, memoranda, messages, minutes of meetings, printed matter, remarks, and speeches by or about individuals and organizations familiar with issues affecting Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty, arranged alphabetically by name of individual or organization
  - Altschul, Frank, 1949-1956 (Folder 27: 1-4)
  - American Committee for Liberation from Bolshevism, 1951-1954 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Berle, Adolf A., 1949-1959 (Folder 27: 6)
  - Bialer, Seweryn, 1956-1963 (Folder 27: 7)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1961 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Buckley, James, 1981-1985 (Folder 27: 9)
  - Clay, Lucius D., 1949-1951 (Folder 27: 10)
  - Collins, Larry D., 1973 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Cummings, Richard S., 1987-1996 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Dulles, Allen W., 1949-1961 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1948-1959 (Folder 28: 4)
  - Eidlin, Fred, 1970-1995 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Freedom House, 1973 (Folder 28: 6)
  - Free Europe Committee, 1956-1964 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Fulbright, J. William, 1967-1979 (Box-folder 29: 1-6)
  - Galantiere, Lewis, 1951-1964 (Folder 29: 7)
  - Gornicki, Wieslaw, 1960-1965 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Grew, Joseph C., 1949-1965 (Box-folder 30: 1-4)
  - Griffith, William E., 1961.; See Zbigniew Brzezinski/box 27
  - Jackson, C. D., 1950-1966 (Folder 30: 5-8)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1973-1987 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Kennan, George F.
    - 1953-1966 (Folder 30: 10-11)
    - 1967-1993 (Box-folder 31: 1-3)
  - Kohler, Foy, 1950-1990 (Folder 31: 4)
  - Lewis, Fulton, 1958 (Folder 31: 5)
  - Michie, Allan A, 1963 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Mickelson, Sig, 1975-1977 (Folder 31: 7)
  - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1952-1954 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Peroutka, Ferdinand, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 32: 1-6)
  - Poole, Dewitt C., 1949-1959 (Folder 32: 7-8)
  - Ramparts, 1967-1979 (Folder 32: 9-11)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 33: 1-3)
  - Sargeant, Howland H., 1957-1984 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Shakespeare, Frank J., 1969-1986 (Folder 33: 5)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1961-1993 (Folder 33: 6-8)
  - Voice of America (VOA)
    - 1947-1982 (Folder 33: 9-11)
    - 1982-1993 (Box-folder 34: 1-3)
  - Walter, Ralph E., 1952-1982 (Folder 34: 4-5)
- Photographs, 1950-1970s.
  20 prints depicting personalities such as James F. Brown, Eleanor Daniels, Juliette Greco, Tom Jones, Martin Luther King, Jan Mekota, Francis Ronalds, Nikolai Safonow, C. Rodney Smith, Peter Zaboji, arranged chronologically
  - 7 prints depicting unidentified individuals, undated (Folder 34: 6)
  - 1 print depicting C. Rodney Smith, president of Radio Free Europe, possibly giving a speech, undated (Folder 34: 7)
  - 1 print depicting Radio Liberty editor Francis Ronalds interviewing Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., undated (Folder 34: 8)
  - 1 print depicting refugee interviews with Fehlhaber, undated (Folder 34: 9)
  - 1 print depicting Eleanor Daniels, secretary to special deputy for Soviet affairs, Munich, undated (Folder 34: 10)
  - 1 print depicting Nougzar Sharia of Radio Liberty's Georgian desk broadcasting news from the West to the listeners in his former homeland in their own language, undated (Folder 34: 11)
  - 1 print depicting unidentified Radio Free Europe editors preparing for the initial broadcast to Romania, 1950 July 14 (Folder 34: 12)
  - 1 print depicting an unidentified Bulgarian announcer at Radio Free Europe during the 1960s (Folder 34: 13)
  - 1 print depicting Archbishop Alexander, head of the Independent Russian Orthodox Church for West Germany and Berlin, having a discussion with Radio Liberty director Richard Bertrandias, while Nikolai Safonow, Press and Public Relations Office, Munich, interprets, during the Archbishop's visit to the Oberwiesenfeld Building, 1961 December 6 (Folder 34: 14)
  - 1 print depicting Talbot Hood interviewing a typical cab driver, with Big Ben and the Parliament building behind them, 1963 February (Folder 34: 15)
  - 1 print depicting Peter Zaboji, Radio Free Europe's Hungarian disc jockey, interviewing Tom Jones during the British singing star's visit to Munich, 1968 March (Folder 34: 16)
  - 1 print depicting Jan Mekota, a Radio Free Europe disc jockey, interviewing Juliette Greco during the French singing star's visit to Munich, 1968 March (Folder 34: 17)
  - 1 print depicting James F. Brown conducting one of Radio Free Europe's daily policy meetings during the 1970s (Folder 34: 18)
  - 1 print depicting an unidentified Kyrgyz broadcaster delivering a news commentary during the 1970s (Folder 34: 19)
- Microfiche from Congressional Information Service Microfiche Library, 1977-1979.
  Arranged chronologically
  - 8 microfiche relating to international affairs, and U.S. Department of State and congressional matters regarding Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty (Folder 34: 20)
- Sound Recordings, 1951-1996 (Box 35-39)
  93 compact sound cassettes recording interviews and speeches of individuals associated with Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty, arranged alphabetically by name of individual or organization
  - Frank, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004863 (Box 35)
  - Andras, Charles, sound recording of interview, 1996 July
    This interview concerns Andras' time at Radio Free Europe. It covers everything from describing day-to-day activities (i.e. life-cycle of a script) to analytical moments (i.e. commenting on the nature of RFE and how this led to them backing organizations they wouldn't back in America). Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004867
  - Andreescu, Gabriel, sound recording of interview, 1994 May 4
    This interview concerns the influence of Radio Free Europe on Andreescu. Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004871
  - Bailey, George, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004872
  - Barthelemy, Tom, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004879
  - Bellus, Samko, sound recording of interview by Russell Poole, 1993 November 24; 1996 July; 3 compact sound cassettes. Use copy reference numbers: 2001c73_a_0004882 and 2001c73_a_0004883
  - Bensi, Giovanni, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004885
  - Berle, P. or Bruce Partu (spelling uncertain), sound recording of interview, 1996 June 19; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004888
  - Borbandi, Gyula, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004892
  - Brown, James, III, sound recordings of interview by Puddington, undated and 1996 April 10
    The 10 April 1996 phone interview concerns Jim Brown's career with Radio Free Europe, beginning with Brown's start in February 1957 through his directorship. Brown describes the circumstance in which he started at RFE. He says he did not intend to be an expert on Eastern European history; that he "stumbled into RFE," having left an academic magazine and simply needing a job. Remarking that he started in the aftermath of the Hungarian Revolution in 1956, he says that event changed a lot of things in RFE. Among other cultural changes, RFE became more interested in research. It wanted to get more facts, rather than propaganda. RFE believed that if a similar debacle ever happened again, it would be the end of RFE. Moreover, he mentions that after 1956, the atmosphere of the programming moved from liberation to gradualism. Eventually, years later, RFE would be really proud of its research product and advertised the academics, etc., that used its information. Much of the time is spent describing the internal culture of the organization. Brown remembers that employees would discuss amongst themselves their opinions about the various issues of the day. However, he notes that there were a series of interdepartmental "cold wars." When he became director, Brown credits himself with making RFE's approach more regional. That is, he thought the various services had been very provincial and only focused on its particular country. He tried to get them to emphasize that all those countries was a part of Europe just as the Western European democracies were. He says the Polish service was the most important service and set the pace for the rest of the organization. Another topic discussed in depth is RFE's connection to the Polish solidarity movement. Within that discussion, Brown credits the Polish church--among other organizations--as acting as a calming agent, as opposed to the more "incendiary" solidarity movement. He feels that together with the solidarity movement and calming agents, RFE helped to exploit cracks in the communist system. The men often discuss their colleagues from the organization, especially Robert Novak. Other items are mentioned in the discussion. RFE had a small Soviet section before the merger with Radio Liberty. Brown knew very little about the connection between RFE and the CIA, but says RFE had a lot of independence. At one point, Brown never thought RFE would bring down the Soviet empire. Finally, RFE had good relations with the consulate. Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0002971
    The undated/1996 phone interview picks up where the April 1996 discussion left off. They discuss Brown's tenure as RFE director in the 1980s. Topics cover the Polish service; Shakespeare, James Buckley, William F. Buckley, and the BIB; why Brown left RFE over a disagreement over the Czechoslovakia desk; RFE's criticism of previous presidents as compared to Reagan; and various directors of RFE. 3 compact sound cassettes. Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0002972
  - Buckley, James, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004897
  - Buell, Bill, and Sig Mickelson sound recording of interviews, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004904
  - Bush, Keith, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004906
  - Carnes, Lord, sound recording of interview, 1994 May 16; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005013
  - Carp, Mircea, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005021
  - Corti, Mavic, and Uldis Grava, sound recording of interviews, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0004859
  - Crusade for Freedom sound recording, 1951-1952 (Box 36)
    Program describes Radio Free Europe and Crusade For Freedom, fighting the Cold War via radio. Includes a dramatization of what it is like to listen to radio in the USSR, an example of Communist radio jamming, a popular song produced by RFE, a freedomgram, reports from the heads of different RFE services. Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0001275
  - Cummings, Richard, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005037
  - Davies, Richard, sound recording of interview, 1996 May 22; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005040
  - Davis, John R. (ambassador), and Robert Byrnes sound recording of interviews, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005043
  - Deák, Isztuan sound recording of interview, 1990 April 27; 1996 April 2; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005046
    Also contains sound recording of the Committee for the Free World, 27 April 1990
  - Deming, Gerd von, sound recording of interview, 1994 June 6; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005053
  - Dunning, John, sound recording of interview, April 4; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005055
  - Ekecs, Geza, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005063
  - Ekmanis, sound recording of interview, 1996 May 30; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005224
  - Fedoseyev, Rachel, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005228
  - Ferguson, Glen, sound recording of interview, undated
  - Floda, Liviu, sound recording of interview, 1996 June 13; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005238
  - Forbes, Steve, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005267
  - Goble, Paul, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005268
  - Gawlikowski, Leszek, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005269
  - Gauebau, Isztvau, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005270
  - Gillette, Robert and David Abshire sound recording of interviews, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005271
  - Girnius, Kestutis, and Nester Ratesh sound recording of interviews, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005273
  - Griffith, Bill, sound recording of interview, undated; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005446 (Box 37)
  - Sound recording of speech to the entire staff of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1979-1980; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005231
    The speech focuses on the RFE/RL budget, employment, and the future of the organization. This talk was likely given in either 1979 or 1980. The cassette is labeled, in error, as an undated interview with Glen Gerguson at the Hilton Hotel in Munich.
  - Handler, Yuri, sound recording of interview, 1996 July; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005457
  - Henze, Paul, sound recording of interview, undated and 1994 April 20; 3 compact sound cassettes. Use copy reference numbers: 2001c73_a_0005460, 2001c73_a_0005465 and 2001c73_a_0005468
  - Hutchings, Robert, James Wilburn, and Marina Vladimir sound recording of interview, 1996 April 19; undated; Hutchings interview is 19 April 1996; the others are undated. Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005472
  - Ilves, Tom, sound recording of interview, 1996 April 16; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005476
  - Jezdinski(?), sound recording of interview, 1994 May 2; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005479
  - Johnson, A. Ross, sound recording of interview, 1996 April 18; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005481
    This interview concerns his work at Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty. Though it touches on his earlier three-year service, the bulk of the interview concerns his time in the 1980s and 1990s.
  - Kalabinski, Jacek, sound recording, 1996 April 3; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005482
    Kalabinski speaks about Polish and Czech events and the influence of Radio Free Europe on them.
  - Karpinski, Jakub, and Dave Evanier sound recording of interview, 1996 April 1; 1991 June 9; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005484
    The Karpinski interview was recorded over the telephone on 1 April 1996; Dave Evanier was recorded on the Mike Feder show on 1 June 1991.
  - Kastner, Al, sound recording of interview, 1996 April 4; Use copy reference number: 2001c73_a_0005487